# **Patrick Coffey**

Ballard Hill, Belvelly, Cobh, Co. Cork 085 240 4011

Patrickcoffey167@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-coffey-72b60a288

## **Personal Profile**

As a recent Bachelor of Commerce graduate from University College Cork and incoming PwC consultant, I bring a solid foundation in Data Analytics, IT, and Finance honed through internship experience. Passionate about making a positive impact in society, I'm currently learning web development as part of the Fáilte Abhaile non-profit foundation and Python to enhance analytical capabilities for a Business Analyst role.

## Education

# <u>2020 – 2024: Bachelor's degree in Commerce, University College Cork</u>

Core Subjects: Accounting, Economics, Law, Information Systems, Marketing, Management.

Grade: Second Class Honours, Grade 1.

# **Projects**

**Group Case Study Capstone:** Team lead of a case study project featuring an analysis of L'Oréal's strategic and financial positioning using consultancy frameworks, offering recommendations designed to boost revenue by 20% using financial models I personally developed.

### 2019 – 2020: Level 5 degree in Business, Cork College of Commerce

**Core Subjects:** Accounting, Economics, Statistics, Business Administration, Spreadsheets, Communication, Marketing.

**Grade:** First Class Honours

## <u>Skills</u>

- **Technical Skills:** Extensive experience with Microsoft 365 including Excel, PowerPoint as well as Azure and Power BI. Currently developing skills in web development and Python, including creating a PDF scraper in Visual Studio to automate data collection and enhance analytical capabilities to drive data-based decision making.
- Client Relationship Communication: Received positive Workday and Snapshot feedback for building strong client and colleague relationships during my time at PwC. Additionally, I have extensive experience in customer service from 2019 to 2022, including key holding and endof-day cash up at Timberland Cork.
- Audit Training: Prior to my summer internship in PwC Risk Assurance, I was given a week of training from PwC utilising the Audit software "Aura" where I learned how to break down complex problems through logical problem solving and communicate findings to clients.

# **Work Experience**

### September 2023 to August 2024 – University College Cork, Cork City, Staff IT Helpdesk

- Provided a high level of customer service by troubleshooting IT problems for staff promptly and professionally and met customer engagement KPIs
- Demonstrated teamwork by liaising with senior teams to solve complex incidents by escalating tickets beyond the remit of the helpdesk
- Updated ongoing tickets with relevant information including personal user data or information relevant to troubleshoot the IT incident

## March 2023 to September 2023 – PwC, Cork City, Government and Health Consulting, Placement

**Health Performance Visualisation Platform (HPVP):** Acted as the primary client liaison, collaborating with a vendor to quantitatively track HSE User Access to SystemView

- Maintained the SharePoint Database of User Access forms, created analytics dashboards, and met required User Access tracking KPIs
- Demonstrated teamwork by liaising with the client to provide analytics to support the integration of an automated Azure Dev Ops tracker to improve the User Access information system
- Developed several slide decks for the client and presented findings in client meetings **HSE PMO Account:** Worked closely with PMO account team generating financial reports related to HSE engagements to support strategic planning and resource allocation
- Produced and analysed financial statements including invoices, expenses, and report generation utilising data from ERP software
- Utilised financial statements to assist with month end financial processes such as provisions and HSE engagement staffing budget
- Consistently delivered accurate financial insights to directors to streamline decision making June 2022 to July 2022 PwC, Cork City, IT Risk Assurance, Summer Internship
  - Collaborated with a team on the planning phase of University Limerick's IT Environment and Cyber Security General Controls Audit working closely with the client
  - Demonstrated attention to detail and problem solving by researching risks and filling out EGAs accurately using documentation from the organisation
  - Took notes in client walkthroughs, created questionnaires, requesting documents and minutes professionally while checking for material misstatements
  - Complied with and learned about IFRS, and ISO regulations to ensure client compliance

### **Interests and Achievements**

**Volunteering** – Currently learning web development for the Fáilte Abhaile foundation's future website and phone app, aiming for 501(C)(3) status in the United States. Volunteered in the Aisling Project at the Ballymun East Child and Youth Centre and ConnectHER during my time at PwC.

**UCC Leadership and Societies** – Former UCC QQI Ambassador Executive Chair where I lobbied UCC to add a help page to the student dashboard providing support to ease the transition to university from QQI degree intake. Member of Commerce, Consulting, and Accounting & Finance societies.

**Web Development** – Currently learning HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python to improve technical skills, personal portfolio website available at <a href="https://github.com/PatrickBcomm">https://github.com/PatrickBcomm</a> and demos on LinkedIn.

**E Learning Certificates** – Acquired nine Kubicle certificates in data literacy and Excel skills for professional development and have also completed PwC's AML and CTF training twice.